翻译  卫老哥
翻译  香茗小焙
翻译  章鱼X
翻译  某豚
翻译  小饭
翻译  噎死青春
翻译  泽川
时间轴  旅行的木讷
后期  饿得慌
特效  宝宝
顾问  老杜
校对  草草
总监  草草
纸牌屋
第二季  第五集
人人影视倾情奉献
进来
冯先生  时间到了
一万
走吧
向阿波马托克斯最后的血腥进军在这里发起
Here began the last bloody march toward Appomattox
而格兰特将军与李将军就在那里首次碰面
where General Grant met General Lee for the first time.
勇敢的人们用鲜血铸就历史
And brave men bled, set the course of history.
我很荣幸能够来到这里
I'm so honored to be here,
纪念陆路战役150周年
celebrating the 150th anniversary of the Overland Campaign.
感谢郡长罗伯茨
Thank you to County Administrator Roberts,
感谢所有热忱的情景重现演员
to all the dedicated re-enactors,
当然  还要感谢
and, of course,
奥基弗州长组织了如此精彩的三日活动
to Governor O'Keefe for organizing such a wonderful three-day event.
说完了吗  先生
Oh. That's all, sir?
说完了  短小精悍
That's it. Short and sweet.
至少很短小
Or at least it's short.
加夫尼的人称内战为"北方侵略战争"
In Gaffney, people called it the "War of Northern Aggression."
个人而言  我并不以南部邦联为荣
I personally take no pride in the Confederacy.
打不赢的仗就不要打
Avoid wars you can't win,
更不要为奴隶制这样愚蠢的原因而战
and never raise your flag for a asinine cause like slavery.
-他就来  -好
- He's on his way. - Fine.
人们会忘记这事的
People will move on.
不会的  你说的越少  他们越会去挖掘
They won't. The less you say, the more they'll dig.
那就让他们挖
Let them.
薇拉  能让我们单独待会儿吗
Willa, could you give us two seconds?
我就在外面
I'll be right outside.
麦金尼斯的事发生在大学时期
McGinnis happened in college.
堕胎则是五年之后的事
The abortion happened five years later.
没有留下任何病历
There aren't any medical records.
完全没有吗
None at all?
我们特别确保了这一点
We specifically made sure.
护士呢  等候室的人呢
A nurse? Somebody in the waiting room?
只有医生一个人在场
The doctor was the only one there.
那他现在在哪里
Then where is he now?
已经是很久以前的事了  康纳  他去世了
It's a long time ago, Connor. He passed away.
如果我都不担心  那你也不必
And if I'm not worried, you shouldn't be.
就算如此  性侵的事现在成为焦点了
Even still, sexual assault is part of the conversation now.
所有的文章和专栏都会提到你
Every article and column mentions you.
如果我们不提供素材  就无法塑造你的形象
If we offer nothing, we can't shape your image.
我说的很清楚  我不想曝光
I made it very clear I don't want exposure.
等我们有新东西可说的时候  我们再说
When we have something new to say, we'll say it.
薇拉  参谋长联席会议那边怎么样了
Willa. Any luck with the Joint Chiefs?
主席办公室还是说他没空
The Chairman's Office still says he's unavailable.
但他们说可以派参谋部主任过来
But they did offer to send the Director of the Joint Staff,
明天上午11点
11:00 a.m. tomorrow.
定下来
Confirm it.
我们去白宫西楼弗兰西斯的办公室见
We'll meet in Francis' office at the West Wing.
还有别的事吗
Anything else?
没了  我该出发了
No. I should get going, hit the road.
谢谢你  康纳
Thank you, Connor.
接通布鲁克斯议员女士的电话
Get Congresswoman Brooks on the phone.
看看第一夫人今天下午是否有空
And see if the First Lady will be available this afternoon.
你想要给中国所有参加峰会的人做简报吗
You want a brief on everyone on the Chinese side of the Summit?
不  杜兰特在华盛顿做的只是表面功夫
No. What Durant's doing in Washington is just the facade.
这可是真正的谈判
This is the real negotiation.
把你手上关于冯的资料都给我
Give me what you have on Feng.
冯山德  家族在共产党内很有影响
Xander Feng. Deep family connections to the Party.
他祖父曾跟毛泽东肩并肩作战
Grandfather fought side by side with Mao.
在电信业势力很大
Big in the telecom industry.
净资产估计有五百亿
Estimated net worth is over 50 billion.
比雷蒙德还有钱
More than Raymond's.
多几十亿  但谁在乎呢
By a few billion. But who's counting?
除了稀土金属精炼厂之外
Do they have any other business partnerships
他们还有其他商业合作吗
other than the Rare Earth Refinery?
我没有发现
Not that I could find.
好吧  向杜兰特询问一下进度
All right. Get a progress update from Durant.
告诉她我们一得知冯的要求就通知她
Tell her I'll be in touch as soon as we know what Feng wants.
雷蒙德·塔斯克这样的人涉足外交事务
When a man like Raymond Tusk gets involved in state diplomacy,
绝不是为了获得诺贝尔和平奖
you can be sure he's not after the Nobel Peace Prize.
他是个机会主义者  但我也是
He's an opportunist. But so am I.
也许这是我的机会  能让他放松对总统的控制
Maybe this is my opportunity to loosen his grip on the President.
副总统先生  你什么时候回华盛顿
Mr. Vice President, when are you returning to Washington?
-副总统先生  你是否...  -副总统先生
- Mr. Vice President, are you... - Mr. Vice President,
你会在斯波特瑟尔韦尼亚待多久
do you have any idea how long you'll be in Spotsylvania?
对于跟中国的谈判有什么看法吗
Any comments on the talks with the Chinese?
能否就即将到来的峰会谈判发表一下看法
Can we get a comment on the upcoming Summit talks?
副总统今天
Vice President will be working
将在自己的房间里办公
from his room for the remainder of the day.
有消息再通知你们
We'll let you know.
先生  你什么时候回华盛顿
Sir, when are you returning to Washington?
冯先生  很高兴见到你
Mr. Feng. It's a pleasure.
彼此彼此  副总统先生
Likewise, Mr. Vice President.
喝咖啡还是喝茶
Coffee? Tea?
有人问过了  谢谢
I've already been offered, but thank you.
谢谢你  密查姆
Thank you, Meechum.
从北京飞过来时间很长
It's a long flight from Beijing.
你一定累坏了
You must be exhausted.
我一直按西方时间作息
I keep Western hours.
和你们没有时差
My midnight is your midnight.
你已经看过计划书了吗
So, have you had a chance to look over the proposal?
看了
I have.
我们开始吧
Shall we?
第四页
Page four.
精炼厂
The refinery.
与塔斯克先生合作
With Mr. Tusk.
与竞标价最高的人合作
With the highest bidder.
我们准备与克雷顿-维斯特签订一份
We're prepared to offer Clayton West
梅梅稀土金属精炼厂的40年租约
a 40-year lease on the Mei Mei Rare Earth Elements Refinery.
租约上会有我的名字
To which I will lend my name.
我知道你和雷蒙德是生意伙伴
I understand that you and Raymond are business associates,
但你还是得公开招标
but you're gonna have to open it up to bidding.
塔斯克先生出价肯定比其他人高
Mr. Tusk will outbid any competitors.
尽管如此  过场还是得走
Well, even so, you know, for appearances.
好吧  过场  如果你坚持
Yes. Appearances. If you must.
那这里就没问题了
So, there are no issues here, then?
我们继续吧
We may proceed.
第六页
Page six.
大桥
The bridge.
财政部外资投资管理委员会将批准
The Committee on Foreign Investment will approve
一项基础建设示范工程
a pilot infrastructure project
建设一座从杰斐逊港到米尔福德市
to build a bridge over the Long Island Sound,
横跨长岛海峡的大桥
from Port Jefferson to Milford,
以25年的过桥收费权作为交换
in exchange for a 25-year toll-taking contract.
在我们考虑大桥前
Before we consider the bridge,
我想先讨论另一件事
there's one more item I'd like to discuss.
"考虑"  我以为大桥的事已经定了
"Consider"? I thought the bridge was definite.
没什么是确定的
Nothing is definite.
这座大桥是首要任务
This bridge is a priority-one item.
对你们总统非常重要  我明白
It's very important to your President. I understand.
你想讨论什么
What would you like to discuss?
你们在世界贸易组织
The currency manipulation suit which
指控我们进行汇率操纵
you have filed against us in the World Trade Organization.
我们已经同意
Which we are prepared to drop
如果满足其他条件就撤销指控
if all other conditions are met.
我们这次会面就是为了讨论
The point of this meeting is to allow us
不适合在正式场合谈论的事  对吗
to say things that cannot be said in formal settings, yes?
是的  当然
Yes. Of course.
我们不希望你们撤诉
We don't want you to drop the lawsuit.
抱歉  我
Forgive me. I...
我不明白
I don't understand.
别在世贸组织让步
Do not back off in the WTO.
但你们在汇率操纵上
But you've been fighting us
已经和我们斗争多年了
on currency manipulation for years.
自由浮动汇率是大势所趋
A free-floating currency is inevitable.
这下我有下手的空间了
Now I have something I can work with.
为什么突然改变主意
Why the sudden change of heart?
并不突然  只是我们这些有远见的人
Not sudden, it has taken those of us who are more forward-thinking
花了很多年才说服其他同僚
many years to convince our counterparts.
那中国直接执行就得了
But China could just do it.
你我都清楚  你们不需要世贸组织的裁定
I mean, you know as well as I, you don't require a WTO ruling.
就像你说的  得走过场
Appearances, as you say.
一定要看起来像是受美国逼迫
It's important that it looks like America forced us out,
而不是我们主动投降
not that we gave in.
那我需要时间
Well, I'll need a little more time,
去和总统商量
so that I can brief the President.
我会耐心等待
I'm here for as long as necessary.
无论你要找谁商量
However you would like to communicate,
我都不管
I leave that to you.
谢谢  副总统先生
Thank you, Mr. Vice President.
谢谢  冯先生
Thank you, Mr. Feng.
在加夫尼我们有自己的外交特色
In Gaffney we had our own brand of diplomacy:
一边握手言欢  一边做好准备
Shake with your right hand, but hold a rock in your left.
看看是谁困在这儿了
Well, look who got stuck with the pool.
我们来这儿简直是找虐
We volunteered because we hate ourselves.
南方前线一切顺利吧
All's well on the Southern front?
没新闻就是没新闻
No news is no news.
我听说那里还有火枪呢
Come on. I hear there's muskets out there.
你什么时候能给我们点猛料
When you giving us something real?
我们正身处美丽的斯波特瑟尔韦尼亚
We're here in beautiful Spotsylvania, aren't we?
不过是给成年人玩玩具枪找借口
This is dress-up for grown men with toy guns.
听起来可以写上五百字
Sounds like 500 words to me.
告诉杜兰特除非我们在世贸撤诉
Tell Durant that China won't discuss the bridge
否则中国不愿意谈大桥
unless we drop the WTO suit.
你不是说他们不希望撤诉吗
I thought you said they want to keep it.
冯希望  说明塔斯克希望
Feng does, which means Tusk does.
但我们不知道北京是不是希望
But we don't know if Beijing does.
你觉得冯在撒谎
You think Feng's lying?
开放汇率会导致利率市场化
An open currency could free up interest rates,
减小中国的通货膨胀
reduce inflation in China.
他们两人都能受益
They'd both profit.
如果他们或者我们将了北京的军
If they're forcing Beijing's hand, or we are,
可能在峰会引起混乱
that could throw the Summit into chaos.
正是  冯可能有后台支持
Exactly. Look, Feng may well have support,
但我猜常委会有分歧
but my guess is that the Standing Committee's divided.
不管怎样  我们打他们个措手不及
Either way, we'll throw 'em off balance.
凯茜一宣布  我们就放出撤诉的风声
Let's leak we're dropping the suit as soon as Cathy presents it.
只是诉讼吗  不漏点别的什么
Just the lawsuit? Nothing else in the leak?
暗示与冯有关  但别点名
A hint of Feng, but no names.
让消息传一阵子再说
Let's let this grow on its own.
这回怎样
How was that?
好多了
Much better.
我感觉不错  你怎么看
I feel good. What do you think?
我看你准备好了
I think you're ready.
代码还得准备多久
How long on the code?
只差几个漏洞了
Just a couple of bugs to work out.
我说明天或周三我就能回去
I told them tomorrow or Wednesday.
活儿还没完
Work's not done.
我要是再往后推  你不觉得别人会奇怪吗
If I postpone again, don't you think it'll draw attention? I --
等完事了也就没事了
It'll be done when it's done.
漏洞修复了我就给你发邮件
I'll email you when the bugs are fixed.
挑一个公开的场所  约好时间给你
Somewhere public, a place and time.
你真想这么做吗
Hey, are you sure you wanna do this?
我明白风险多大
I understand the risks.
你自以为明白而已
Well, you think you do.
我也不是头回身陷险境了
This isn't the first time I've been in danger.
是吗  在《先驱报》被纸割伤过手吗
Oh, yeah? Paper cuts at The Herald?
死亡威胁  我揭露了一个特区贩毒集团
Death threats. When I exposed a drug ring in D.C.
我读过你写的报道
You know, I read the articles.
那根本不算什么
That's small time.
我差点就接受司法保护了
I almost had to go into protection.
这可是联调局  不是什么街警
This is the FBI. It's not a few street cops.
你觉得自己反抗当局
You think you're badass because
就是个了不得的义士吗
you're on some vigilante anarchy kick?
起码我有胆子在报道上署上真实姓名
At least I have the balls to put my name on the work I do.
但你没面临过几百年的刑罚
You've never faced a hundred years in prison,
你这自以为是的混蛋
you self-righteous prick.
我大多数朋友被关起来  永远出不来
Most of my friends are locked up and rotting away
就因为他们太多次以身犯险
'cause they poked the bear one too many times.
为什么  因为他们想揭露政府的监控项目
Why? They wanted to expose government surveillance,
棱镜计划  挪用公款  滥用职权  酷刑和欺骗
the PRISM program, embezzlement, abuse, fucking torture, lies.
你是个记者有什么了不起  我们是战士
You're a journalist. Who gives a shit? We're fucking soldiers.
这已经是我生活的一部分了
It's personal for me now.
我没选择了  但你还有
I don't have a choice, but you still do.
我也没选择了
I don't have a choice.
消息从哪来
Where did you get this?
你可以说消息源与中国代表团关系密切
You could say a source close to the Chinese delegation.
给我个名字
Give me a name.
我只知道是一个中国商人
All I know is that it's a Chinese businessman
和常委会关系非同一般  在峰会上进行秘密外交
with ties to the Standing Committee back-channeling the Summit.
-他人在华盛顿吗  -我不知道
- In Washington? - I don't know.
-在和谁接触  -这我也不知道
- With who? - I don't know that either.
如果我去问贸易代表处  他们会证实吗
If I call the USTR's office, they'll confirm?
我知道多少  就告诉了你多少
I'm telling you as much as I know.
你为什么要告诉我
Why are you telling me this at all?
反正明天他们也会把消息放出去
They're going public with it tomorrow anyway.
不如让你抢先发布
You might as well get the scoop.
为什么挑中我
Why me, specifically?
内战重演的报道配不上你这样的记者
You deserve better than a Civil War reenactment.
别装做你突然变成圣诞老人了
Please don't pretend you've suddenly become Santa Claus.
我现在帮你的忙  也许你会承我的情
I give you something now, maybe you'll remember.
将来有一天或许用得上
It's an investment in the future.
我可不太喜欢卖人情
I'm not big on favors.
所以我说了"也许"
I just said "maybe."
马上给我接贸易代表处
Connect me to the USTR's office.
越过新闻发言人
Skip the Press Secretary.
跟他们说我想问世贸组织诉讼的事
Tell them I want to talk about the WTO suit.
你跟谁说了
Who did you speak to?
康纳  他在向艾拉·萨伊德泄露消息
Connor. He's talking to Ayla Sayyad.
你透给他多少
How much did you fill him in?
没说多少
The bare minimum.
要是按之前说好的
I'd be a lot more comfortable
你亲自去说  我会放心许多
if it was you going directly, as we discussed.
这样就牵涉不到我  你也就更安全了
This puts distance on me, which puts distance on you.
你今晚亲自去见冯
I want you to meet with Feng tonight.
-不用中间人  -明白
- No proxies. - Understood.
古德温先生那边办得如何了
Now where are we with Mr. Goodwin?
随时可以下手  判个35年或者无期
Any day now. Thirty-five to life.
网络恐怖主义  判刑都很重
Cyber terrorism. Penalties are stiff.
务必做得干净利落  道格
This needs to be clean, Doug.
会的
It will be.
一击致命
One fall of the axe.
有消息告诉我
Keep me informed.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
我认为你的做法真是太勇敢了
Well, I just think what you did took so much bravery.
在直播节目上  当着全国观众的面
To go on air like that, in front of the whole country,
讲出你的经历
and say what you did?
这对我的确不容易
That means a lot to me.
我很钦佩两位的努力  为了帮助
And I admire what you both have been doing to advocate for the –
那些受害者
well, for the victims.
是女性  就像你和我  不只是受害者
Well, women, like you and me. Not victims.
还有男人  这无关性别
Men, too. It's not gender-specific.
是啊
Well, yes.
你愿意参与进来吗
Would you consider pitching in?
怎么参与
How?
如果有第一夫人支持  我们的表态就有力多了
It would send a strong message if we had the First Lady in our corner.
如果你觉得我能帮上忙的话
If you think I could help.
妇女党团的领袖
Well, if the head of the Women's Caucus,
以及白宫的第一和第二夫人加起来...
both wives from the White House...
这样的组合他们没法无视
That's a meeting they couldn't sweep under the rug.
主席肯派人来  就已经是很好的兆头了
And the fact that the Chairman sent anyone is promising,
但我们得保证他真能听到我们的声音
but we need to make sure our message gets back to him.
只是  我没有过此类经历
I just...I haven't been through the same sort of experience.
这有什么妨碍呢
Well, why should that prevent you?
我不知道我是不是有发言权
I don't know if I have a right to speak about it.
你可是第一夫人
You're the First Lady.
你有权发表任何言论
You have a right to speak about anything you want.
-怀特先生  -马博利太太
- Mr. White? - Mrs. Marbury.
叫我苏珊
I'm Susan.
很高兴见到你
Well, it's a pleasure to meet you.
我知道这里挺偏僻的
I know I'm a little off the beaten path.
找这里困难吗
Did you have any trouble finding me?
不  您给的指示很明确  找起来很轻松
No. The directions were great. Easy as pie.
那就好
Well, good.
请进
Come in.
我得承认  我都期待一整天了
I have to admit I've been looking forward to this all day.
没想到你们这么快就要宣布了
I didn't realize you were announcing so soon.
我们收到了慷慨的捐款
We've had some great luck with the endowment.
我丈夫生前没受到多少嘉奖
Well, my husband didn't get much recognition while he was alive.
计划生育协会想以他来命名基金
I was so thrilled when Planned Parenthood asked to
真让我激动
name a fund after him.
您肯同意  我们也很高兴
Well, we're thrilled that you're open to it.
你之前打电话说有些问题要问
When you called, you said you had some questions?
问题挺敏感的  所以我想亲自来问
They're delicate. That's why I wanted to come in person.
怎么个"敏感"法
"Delicate", how?
很多人会抗议向未成年人
There are a lot of people who will protest
提供这方面的经济资助
this sort of financial assistance to minors.
我们得保证他们找不到诽谤我们的根据
And we want to make sure they have no cause to smear us.
我丈夫这辈子  总有人想诋毁他
People tried to smear my husband his entire career.
他从不让这些事影响他的工作
He never let it affect the work he was doing.
您丈夫实施过任何非法堕胎手术吗
Did your husband ever perform any illegal abortions?
我需要您的答案  马博利太太
I need you to answer me, Mrs. Marbury.
您丈夫实施过任何非法堕胎手术吗
Did your husband perform any illegal abortions?
我不想讨论这个
I won't discuss that.
没有未上报的吗
Nothing unreported?
年轻人  你年纪不大  不会记得
Young man, you're not old enough to remember.
但在过去  人人...
But there was a time when everybody --
有没有涉及什么大人物
What about any prominent figures
能被反堕胎人士拿来当靶子的
who the Anti-Choice crowd could vilify?
没有
No.
马博利医生有没有为克莱尔·安德伍德做过堕胎
Did Dr. Marbury perform an abortion for Claire Underwood?
不  他没有
No, he did not.
我知道他做过
I know for a fact that he did.
这是谎话  我想请你马上离开
That is not true, and I would like you to leave now.
抱歉  马博利太太
Forgive me, Mrs. Marbury.
我对您没说实话
I haven't been entirely honest with you.
我叫赛斯·格雷森
My name's Seth Grayson.
我不为计划生育协会工作
I don't work for Planned Parenthood.
冯先生
国内常委们推测  搞秘密外交的是你
华尔街电讯报
美国在世贸组织撤诉
香港出现了两篇文章
都提到了你的名字
要我联系副总统吗
不  让他来找我
No. Let him come to me.
给塔斯克先生打电话
Get Mr. Tusk on the phone.
你真该为自己感到羞愧
You should ashamed of yourself.
我是为了你好  马博利太太
I'm doing this for your own good, Mrs. Marbury.
想想媒体炒作的后果
Imagine the media frenzy.
您丈夫生前的名声尽毁
Your husband's legacy, destroyed.
媒体日日夜夜追着您不放
The press hounding you, day and night.
计划生育基金  也没有了
And Planned Parenthood Fund, gone.
我怎么知道你是不是为她工作
How do I know you work for her?
而不是什么右翼狂热分子  打算摧毁...
That you're not just some right-wing fanatic who wants to destro?
否则我就不会亲自登门拜访了
Because I wouldn't have done you the courtesy of paying a visit.
来的就不是我
There would've been an army of
而是一队卫星转播车了
satellite trucks at your door instead of me.
我不会告诉任何人的  如果你是担心这个
Well, I won't tell anyone, if that's what you're worried about.
我相信您
I believe you.
您丈夫有没有对他帮助过的女人做过任何记录
Did your husband keep records of any kind of who he assisted?
任何东西  笔记或非公开记录
Anything at all? Notes? Unofficial records?
他有一本日记
He kept a journal.
您还能找到吗
Do you still have it?
我能看看吗
May I?
看吧
Go ahead.
我得把它带走
Oh. I need to take this with me.
你不能把那页撕掉吗
Can't you just take out that page?
如果有人找到这本日记  这几页又缺了
Someone finds this with pages missing,
那会引起怀疑
that could raise eyebrows.
这里面有他60年的人生
There's 60 years of his life in there.
从我们相遇到他去世
From when we met until he died.
那您希望那六十年被遗忘
And do you want six decades
却只剩下25年前8月的一个晚上吗
reduced to one night in August...25 years ago?
想象一下这里当时的情形
Now just imagine what it looked like back then.
山脊边缘是茂密的灌木丛
The edge of the ridge was a dense thicket,
北方军队得以长驱直入  在骡子鞋列队
which allowed the Northern troops to come in and form on the Mule Shoe.
南方军在山脊顶端
Now the Southern regiments were entrenched
这一带挖好了战壕
in this area at the apex of the line.
如您所见
As you can see,
这里的地形迫使双方向下走  逼近彼此
the topography really forced the two sides down towards each other.
这里就是血腥角
This is the Bloody Angle.
没错
That's right.
我昨晚还读到了相关内容
I was reading about it last night.
短兵相接  白刃相见
Close quarters, hand-to-hand combat.
据说  南北双方共有一万五千名士兵
All told, about 15,000 Union-Confederate soldiers
在血腥角这块半英里宽的战场上
lost their lives here at the Bloody Angle, on a battlefield
失去了生命
that's only about half a mile wide.
副总统先生  我们今天为您准备了一份惊喜
Now, Mr. Vice President, we have a surprise for you today.
向您介绍麦高文旅第12军团的
I'd like to introduce you to Corporal Augustus Elijah Underwood
奥古斯都·以利亚·安德伍德下士
of the 12th Regiment of the McGowan Brigade,
您的曾曾曾祖父
your great-great-great-grandfather.
我在这场战役中牺牲于此
I died here in this battle.
我觉得是搞错了吧
I think there's been a mistake.
我祖父从没说过祖上有人参加过内战
My grandfather never mentioned any Underwoods in the war.
我们做过调查
We did our research.
他就是在这里战斗牺牲的
He definitely fought and died here.
我只有24岁  而我儿子
I was 24. And my son,
你的曾曾祖父只有两岁
your great-great-grandfather was two years old.
我从没见过他
I never met him.
就是在这里吗  在血腥角
It happened here, at the Bloody Angle?
在那片林子边上
At the edge of those woods.
我的脑袋被石头砸扁了
My skull was bashed in with a rock.
奥古斯都  谢谢你
Augustus, thank you.
这边  还有一些
Now, uh, over here we've got something that's,
有趣的东西
uh, very interesting as well.
等一下
Uh, j—just a moment.
接着说
Tell me more.
当时正是半夜
It was the middle of the night.
我们的子弹打光了  只剩下刺刀
And we were out of musket balls, just bayonets.
而且只有一半人有刺刀  我什么都没有
Only half of us had those. I had nothing.
只能靠这双手
Just these hands.
天很黑  什么都看不见
So dark, couldn't see nothing.
但能听北方佬在朝我们跑来
But you could hear 'em, the Yanks, runnin' toward us.
接着就能闻到他们了
And then you could smell 'em.
我遇到的第一个北方佬
First Yank that brushed up against me,
被我掐住了脖子  倒在地上
I grab him by the throat, fall down on the ground.
我用力打他  打到皮开肉绽
I bit him so hard, I could taste the bone.
然后他抓起一块石头  砸中了这里
Then he grabs a rock and brings it down right here.
我就这么死了
And that was that.
我被埋在万人冢里  没有墓碑
I was buried in a mass grave, no headstone.
能给您和奥古斯都拍张合影吗
Could we get a picture with you and Augustus?
好
Yes.
谢谢你
Thank you.
他相当认真啊
He takes it rather seriously.
是啊  他们都很认真
Oh, yeah. They all do.
前面有我们重建的
Now, up ahead, we have examples of,
邦联军壁垒的模型
uh, Confederate ramparts that we've reconstructed.
可以看到他们是如何伐木挖战壕的
And you can see how they cut the timber and made the trenches.
在战斗过程中
Now these trenches traded hands
这些战壕几次易手
many times over the course of the battle.
你有钥匙
You have keys.
你归我们管  没错  我们有钥匙
We own you. Yes, we have keys.
我去把衣服穿上
I'm gonna put some clothes on.
别想衣服的事了
Forget your clothes.
你的原话"你真想这么做吗"
And I quote, "You sure you wanna do this?"
"我没选择了  但你还有"
And I quote, "I don't have a choice, but you do."
你他妈以为自己在干什么
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
他应该知道他究竟要做什么
He should know what he's getting into.
这是丝绸睡裤吗
Are those silk pajamas?
近距离看更有档次了
Looks even fancier in person.
腰果
Cashew.
不  别碰她
No. Don't touch her.
过来  小家伙
Hey, there, little guy.
我以前在监控里见过你
I've seen you before on camera, hmm?
请把她放下
Please put her down.
不要冒险
Don't take the chance.
这这双鞋是在彭尼百货公司买的
I bought these shoes at J.C. Penney,
含税价72块
$72 with tax.
橡胶鞋底  用水就能冲干净
Rubber soles. You can clean 'em off with a hose.
求求你  你弄伤她了
Please, you're hurting her.
我也有一只宠物  他叫嘉文·奥尔西
I have a pet, too. His name is Gavin Orsay.
坐下
Sit.
我说"坐下"
I said, "Sit."
瞧瞧你多乖呀  嘉文
Look what a good boy you are, Gavin.
你想让我这么做吗
Is that what you need me to do?
安静  我说"去捡"  你就去
Quiet. When I say "fetch," you fetch.
现在我们去抓卢卡斯  就像我们说好的那样
And now we are going to fetch Lucas, just like we discussed.
你要是敢咬我  我就杀了你
If you try to bite my hand, I will put you to sleep.
介意我拿两瓶吗
Mind if I take a couple?
道格·斯坦普  我是副总统的幕僚长
Doug Stamper, I'm the Vice President's Chief of Staff.
我知道  坐吧
I know. Sit down.
我祖父参加过革命
My grandfather fought in the Revolution.
中国当时很穷
China was poor, then.
很难买到糖
Sugar was hard to come by.
现在中国到处能买到糖
Now sugar's everywhere in China.
要来杯古典鸡尾酒吗
Do you like Old-Fashioneds?
不  谢谢
No, thanks.
我看到新闻了
I've seen the news.
你们政府对我们撤诉非常高兴
Your government was enthusiastic about our dropping the suit.
他们还在国内将其鼓吹为一场胜利
They've touted it as a victory back home.
确实是胜利  但不是我们想要的胜利
It is a victory, but not the victory we wanted.
这让我们很难相信
We're finding that difficult to believe.
你说我们  是指副总统吧
By "we," you mean the Vice President.
我指的是美国政府
I mean the American government.
他声称自己就代表美国政府
Which he proclaims to represent.
没错  而我代表他
He does. And I'm representing him.
斯坦普先生  别吹嘘你的地位
Don't inflate your status, Mr. Stamper.
你不过是个跑腿的
You're nothing but an errand boy.
你要对副总统说什么吗
Do you have a message for the Vice President?
如果他代表美国政府
If he represents the American government,
那他为什么没能转达我的要求
then why did he fail to communicate my request?
我们质疑你的合法性  冯先生
We question your legitimacy, Mr. Feng.
你们代表团的做法和言论
Nothing your delegation has done or said has,
都与你的要求背道而驰
in any way, supported your requests.
闻闻
Smell that.
我用了高档珍稀的麦卡伦
I use Macallan Rare and Fine,
1926年产  一瓶四万美金
1926. $40,000 a bottle.
你以前酗酒  是吗
You used to be an alcoholic, correct?
酒瘾是戒不掉的  只能克制
Not "used to be." Still am. A sober one.
你怀念这味道吗
Do you miss it?
那可是五千美元
Five thousand dollars you just spilled.
我会寄张支票给你
I'll send you a check.
我喜欢你  斯坦普先生  即便你只是个跑腿的
I like you, Mr. Stamper, even if you're just an errand boy.
我再问你一次
I'll ask you again.
你要对副总统说什么吗
What is your message for the Vice President?
恢复起诉  否则杰斐逊港大桥项目将取消
There will be no Port Jefferson Bridge unless the lawsuit is reintroduced.
到时  常委会会有人抗议
When you do, there will be those on the Standing Committee who protest,
我会搞定他们
but I'll manage them.
大多数人想要改革
The majority want reform.
我会告诉副总统
I'll tell the Vice President.
斯坦普先生  还有一条
Mr. Stamper, one more message.
请提醒副总统  我们来这里
Please remind the Vice President that we are both here
是应我们共同的朋友塔斯克先生的邀请
at the behest of our mutual friend, Mr. Tusk.
如果副总统不愿意合作  我就直接跳过他
If the Vice President fails to cooperate, I will simply bypass him.
怎么了
Yes?
是道格
It's Doug.
好吧
Fine.
跟冯谈了
Spoke with Feng.
给你的洋葱圈
Here's your onion rings.
你知道朗斯特里特将军就是在这里
Did you know that General Longstreet was shot here,
被他自己人意外误伤害死的
accidentally, by his own men in the dark?
不  我不知道
No...I didn't.
好吧  跟我介绍一下进展吧
All right. Bring me up to date.
跟冯谈得怎么样了
Where are we with Feng?
他要我们恢复诉讼
He wants us to resume the lawsuit.
看来他要坚持立场
So, he's sticking to his guns.
我们不起诉  大桥项目就取消
If we don't reintroduce it, there's no bridge project.
那样总统会很失望
Well, that would greatly upset the President.
要我转达冯的意思吗
Do you want me to deliver Feng's message?
绝对不要
Absolutely not.
我们就要让总统生气
We want the President angry.
不过要想办法不让他怪罪在我身上
The tricky part is making sure he doesn't direct it toward me.
那你要我做什么
So what do you want me to do?
联系凯茜的人
Get a hold of Cathy's people.
决不能提及诉讼
Do not mention the lawsuit at all.
让他们自己提大桥项目
Have them bring up the bridge instead.
看看冯是不是在虚张声势
Let's see if Feng is bluffing.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
得吸取朗斯特里特的教训  他树大招风
We must learn from Longstreet. He rode too high in the saddle.
如果明天有人朝我开枪
If a bullet comes my way tomorrow,
那绝不会是意外  而且我得赶快躲开
it will not be an accident, and I must be quick to duck.
先生们  感谢你们的到来
Gentlemen, thank you for coming.
副总统会出席吗
Is the Vice President attending?
不会  他不在华盛顿
No, he's not. He's out of town.
我只是决定用他的办公室
I just decided to use his office
因为他的比我的大得多
because it's a bit bigger than mine.
请坐吧
Please, sit.
我知道这不是你们第一次
I know this isn't the first conversation
谈性侵犯的问题
you've had about sexual assault.
我们和议员女士
We've had a very open dialogue
已经进行了一段时间的公开对话了
with the Congresswoman for quite some time.
可以说"公开"
"Open" is one way to put it.
我倒觉得参谋长联席会议只是在默默忍受我
I think the Joint Chiefs have tolerated my concerns, but
公平来讲  我们一直有做出积极回应
To be fair, we've been quite responsive.
过去两年里...
Over the past two years alone, we --
议员女士对我表达了她的沮丧
The Congresswoman has expressed her frustration to me
因为这件事上仍有改进空间
that there's still room for improvement.
安德伍德夫人  我能说几句吗
Mrs. Underwood, if I may.
请讲
Please.
这件事我们十分看重
This is an issue we've grappled with seriously.
我们增加了相关教育和防范措施
Increased education and prevention measures,
整改汇报流程
restructuring the reporting process,
杜绝军事法庭的滥用职权现象
insulating courts martial from abuse of power.
但还是不够
It's still not enough.
我们不会进行民事审判的
Civilian jurisdiction is not gonna happen.
我们都清楚这是议员女士所希望的
We're all aware that's what the Congresswoman would prefer,
但我们不会允许我们...
but we won't allow our cha--
我迟到了吗
Am I late?
是我的错  会面提前了
It's my fault. The meeting got pushed up.
我本想给你发邮件的  非常抱歉
I meant to email you. I'm very sorry.
没关系  请坐
That's fine. Please, sit.
我们不知道您也会来  沃克夫人
We didn't know you'd be attending, Mrs. Walker.
抱歉打断你们了
I'm sorry for interrupting.
请继续
Continue.
正如我刚刚所说
As I was saying,
将性侵案件的审判权完全交给民事法庭
putting sexual assault cases entirely in the hands of civilian courts
从根本上侵蚀了军队自我约束的能力
fundamentally erodes the military's ability to self-discipline.
那要是实施民事监管  而不是民事法庭呢
What about civilian oversight instead of civilian courts?
任何让步  都会一发不可收拾
That's a slippery slope.
对于种族融合  也曾有人说过类似的话
There were those who said the same about racial integration.
融合没有改变核心的运作本质...
Integration didn't change the core operational nature of the --
但的确证明了军方可以实现自我改革
But it did prove that the military could shape its own evolution.
那是没错  但就这个问题
Absolutely. But in this case,
民事监管不是解决办法
civilian oversight is not the answer.
我丈夫没有军衔  但他监管军方
My husband is a civilian who oversees the military.
你难道想说
Are you suggesting that
民众在这种问题上无从提供指导吗
civilians can offer no guidance in matters like this?
抱歉  沃克夫人  我完全不是那个意思
Forgive me, Mrs. Walker. I didn't mean to suggest that at all.
那或许你该听听你对面的民众是怎么想的
Then maybe you should listen to the civilian sitting across from you.
当然  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
这是你们出版的性侵防范读物
This is from your own sexual assault prevention literature.
上面写道  有些情况下
And in it, it says in some cases
更应该屈从  而不是抵抗
it may be advisable to submit than to resist.
所以我想  这方面显然还有可以改进的地方
I think it's quite clear that there's still room for improvement.
你知道冯山德吗
Did you know about Xander Feng?
在新闻上看到才知道的
Not 'til I saw his name on the wire.
美联社  路透社等大新闻通讯社发布的新闻  媒体获得后会进行转载
他曾两次被指控腐败
He's been charged with corruption twice.
两次指控都撤销了
Both times the charges were dropped.
你知道在中国获罪后会怎样吗
Do you know what happens in China if you're convicted?
-我猜不会有好事  -判死刑
- I'm guessing it's not good. - You die.
我说对了
There you go.
这人如果再上"过场法庭"
We're talking about a man who's only one kangaroo court
指完全是摆摆样子的法庭  根本不会认真按照法律进行审判
就必死无疑
away from lethal injection,
而且他富可敌国  腐败昭然若揭
who's filthy rich and clearly corrupt.
中方就派这样的人来吗
And this is who the Chinese send?
你问错人了
You're asking the wrong guy.
别再躲躲闪闪了
Stop dodging.
我不过是传了个话  仅此而已
I passed a note in class. That's all.
我们信任你  弗兰克
We placed our faith in you, Frank.
我们还有今明两天时间  总统先生
We still have the rest of the day and all of tomorrow, Mr. President.
我需要这座桥
I need this bridge.
否则我的基建项目就得叫停
Otherwise, we have to stall my infrastructure program.
没有外国投资  没法削减赤字
No foreign investment, no deficit reduction.
中方知道这一点
And the Chinese know this.
他们就是拿这个做筹码
They're using it for leverage.
但是为了什么呢
Yeah, but for what?
我也不清楚
Well, that I'm not sure of.
那我们派你去斯波特瑟尔韦尼亚干什么  弗兰克
Then why did we send you to Spotsylvania, Frank?
这些问题你该心里有数的
You're supposed to have answers to these questions.
总统先生  我一小时前和冯先生联系过
Mr. President, I spoke to Mr. Feng an hour ago.
他怎么说
What'd he say?
子弹来了
Here comes the bullet.
他说弗兰克没表达清楚他的意思
He claims that Frank hasn't been delivering his messages properly.
我已经逐字复述了他的要求
I have conveyed his requests word for word.
他说  你一直在唱反调
He says you've been doing the opposite.
究竟是谁在负责私下沟通  我还是雷蒙德
Whose responsible for the back-channeling here, me or Raymond?
你  弗兰克
You are, Frank.
我只是来帮忙的  不是来谈判的
I'm simply here to facilitate, not negotiate.
可你还继续私下联系
And yet you continue to have private conversations with
北京所谓的密使
Beijing's supposed emissary.
听着  弗兰克
Listen, Frank --
你要信任冯先生  而不是我吗  雷蒙德
Are you prepared to trust Mr. Feng's word over mine, Raymond?
没人质疑你的话  弗兰克
No one is doubting your word, Frank.
如果冯真的是为了他政府的利益
Well, if Feng is truly representing his government's interest,
为什么他在我这儿一套  雷蒙德那儿一套
then why is he telling Raymond one thing and telling me another?
那大桥项目取消是怎么回事
How do you explain the bridge falling through?
自由浮动汇率能让他受益
Well, he personally profits from a free-floating currency,
和他合作的人都是如此
just as anyone would who's in business with him,
就比如你  雷蒙德
such as yourself, Raymond.
精炼厂和大桥是两码事
The refinery and the bridge are two completely different issues.
我们先说桥的事
Let's keep our focus, here.
必须重谈建桥的事  没得商量
I want the bridge back on the table, end of story.
-凯瑟琳  -我明早第一个提这件事
- Catherine? - It'll be the first item I bring up in the morning.
弗兰克  先按兵不动  别联系冯
Frank, stay put for now. But don't contact Feng.
你也是  雷蒙德
And that goes for you, too, Raymond.
建桥的事谈妥之前不许你们再私下会面
I don't want any more back-channeling until the bridge is revived.
凯瑟琳  有什么事直接和我说
And, Catherine, you communicate directly with me.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
那就先说到这里了
All right. We're done here.
第一滴血溅了出来
The first drops of blood have been spilt.
子弹擦过我的脸颊  但我没有倒下
Bullet grazed my cheek, but I haven't fallen.
道格  想个办法让我见到冯
Doug, find me a way to meet Feng.
有件事我们得先谈谈
We need to discuss something first.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我刚跟一个叫赛斯·格雷森的人通了电话
I just got off the phone with a guy named Seth Grayson.
我和我丈夫聊过了
I've spoken with my husband.
道格说了  感谢你能见我
Doug told me. Thank you for fitting me in today.
-是这个吧  -86年8月
- Is that it? - August '86.
我们凭什么相信你
And why should we trust you?
有些证据康纳没能抹去
There was evidence that Connor didn't make disappear.
我本可以把这个拿给《美国周刊》
I could've taken this to Us Weekly
报酬够我买新房了
and bought a new house.
可我把它带来给您
Instead, I brought it to you.
我当时面试的时候你为什么没申请
And why didn't you apply when I was interviewing candidates?
申请了也没用  薇拉不喜欢我
There's no point. Willa doesn't like me.
她怕我
I intimidate her.
这日记就是我的简历
That journal is my version of a resume.
或是勒索信
Or extortion.
我没想勒索您  安德伍德夫人
I'm not extorting you, Mrs. Underwood.
我只是想强调
I'm just highlighting the difference
好的决定和正确决定的差别
between a good choice and the right choice.
那你说解雇刚聘用三个月的媒体主管
And tell me, how would we handle the repercussions
所带来的影响我们要怎么应对
of firing our comm director three months after we hire him.
您不用解雇他
You don't fire him.
您告诉他雇用我是为了减轻工作量
You tell him that you're bringing me on board to help with the workload.
他还负责您  我负责您丈夫
He stays on with you. I cover your husband.
康纳不会喜欢和我合作的
Connor will hate working with me.
过几个月我再找人来挖他墙角
I'll arrange a job offer elsewhere in a few months.
到那时  他会愿意接受的
By the time it comes in, he'll want to move on.
康纳也知道  如何保证他不会公开
Connor knows. What's to prevent him from going public?
我能搞定康纳·埃利斯
I can handle Connor Ellis.
您只能相信我  我...
You just have to take me on my word on that. I –
我只知道
Here's what I know.
您要弄垮我比我扳倒您容易得多
It is far easier for you to destroy me than the other way around.
我得和我丈夫谈谈
I have to speak to my husband.
没问题
Of course.
我没有复印
I didn't make any copies.
您手上的是唯一的一份
You have the only one.
纯尊尼获加黑牌
Uh, Johnny Walker Black, neat.
-东西在哪  -我口袋里
- Where is it? - It's in my pocket.
给我吧
Come on.
-有问题吗  -没有  一切就绪
- Something up? - No. We're good to go.
你看起来很紧张
You seem nervous.
虽然我干了二十年违法乱纪的事
Just because I've been breaking the law for 20 years
我还是会觉得紧张
doesn't mean I don't still get nervous.
-嘉文  -别说我的名字
- Gavin. - Do not say my name.
看着我
Look at me.
没问题的  我们练习过了
It's gonna be fine. We practiced.
我有信心  会成功的
I'm confident. This is gonna work.
我请你
I got your drink.
他非常有资历
He's more than qualified.
你的直觉怎么说
What do your instincts tell you?
我不想再增加曝光度了
That I just don't wanna end up more exposed.
格雷森都知道了
Well, Grayson already knows.
我们要是不表现出...
I mean, if we don't exhibit some degree of --
让道格去查查他
Have Doug look into him.
看看我们有没有筹码
Let's see if there's some leverage.
但是我们不知道他能查到什么
Yeah, but we don't know what he'll find
什么时候能查到  这期间格雷森又会做什么
or when,  or what he'll do in the meantime.
这让我们无从防备
And that puts us into unchartered territory.
如果我们解雇康纳  他也会告密的
Well, Connor will expose us, too, if we let him go.
处理得好就不会
Not if it goes smoothly.
如果现在拒绝格雷森  我们无法预料后果
If we turn away Grayson now, we can't predict anything.
而且他可比我们要输得起
And, look, he has a lot less to lose than we do.
好吧  我只是不相信他  弗兰西斯
Okay. I just – I don't think we can trust him, Francis.
如果康纳尽了职我们也不会有这麻烦了
We wouldn't be having this conversation if Connor had done his job.
我宁可要个不可信任的手下
And I'd rather manage someone I don't trust
也不要做事不周到的
than someone who is reckless.
好吧  下一步怎么做
Fine. What's the next step?
我先亲自跟格雷森谈谈
I'd like to talk to Grayson myself first,
然后我让道格跟康纳谈谈
and then I'll have Doug talk to Connor.
你那边怎么样
How are you doing?
你关注新闻了吗
You been following the news?
对我们来说是好是坏
Is it bad for us? Or good?
都有可能
Could go either way.
需要我的话就开口
I'm here if you need me.
我明天就回去
I'm back tomorrow.
-我爱你  -我也爱你
- I love you. - Love you, too.
-都准备好了吗  -都准备好了  先生
- We all set? - All set, sir.
走吧
Let's go.
不  把灯关掉
Oh, no, no. Turn those off.
把灯关掉
Turn those off.
他在哪
Where is he?
这边走  先生
Right this way, sir.
奥古斯都会拉小提琴吗
Did Augustus play?
我希望我会
I like to think I did.
你自己的名字是什么
What's your own name?
我在这里的时候  我就是奥古斯都·安德伍德
When I'm here, I'm Augustus Underwood.
你的真名是什么
What's your real name?
你觉得这不真实吗
Doesn't this feel real to you?
你能带我去看他死的地方吗  具体地点
Will you show me where he died? The exact spot.
好的  先生
I will, sir.
我要去向我的祖先致敬
I'm gonna pay respects to my ancestor.
请给我点隐私
I would appreciate a little privacy.
我们在这里等着
We'll wait here.
小约翰在移动
Little John on the move.
就在那些树后
Just beyond those trees.
谢谢你  我自己过去吧
Thank you. I'll be good from here.
没事
We're fine.
希望你没等太久
I hope you haven't waited long.
这里很平静  我不介意
It's peaceful here. I didn't mind.
现在很平静  但有一万五千人曾在这里丧生
Peaceful now. Fifteen thousand men died in these woods.
我的曾曾曾祖父死在我们站的地方
My grandfather's grandfather died where we're standing.
我的祖父在革命中牺牲
My grandfather was killed in the Revolution.
我听说了
So I've heard.
你怕死吗  副总统先生
Do you fear death, Mr. Vice President?
跟其他人一样
No more or less than any man.
死亡给我激励  让我去经历一切
It motivates me. To experience everything,
在一切化为粪土之前  努力成就伟业
accomplish all I can before it all vanishes.
在这方面我觉得我们很像
I think you and I are similar in that regard.
那我们为什么要彼此背道而驰呢
Then why are we working at cross purposes?
你的意思是
Now what you mean is,
为什么我不服从你和塔斯克先生
"Why am I not submitting to you and Mr. Tusk?"
你在破坏谈判
You're sabotaging the negotiations.
而你在利用谈判达到自己的目的
And you're using them for your own personal ends.
错了  我花了七年时间说服常委
Wrong. It's taken me seven years to convince the Standing Committee
这才是应该采取的做法
that this was the right course of action.
可以给你和塔斯克带来数十亿收益的做法
A course of action that will earn you and Tusk billions.
你约我在这里见面就为了攻击我吗
Why did you want this meeting? Just to attack me?
为了给雷蒙德带个信
To send a message to Raymond.
美国总统和我不是他的傀儡
The President of the United States and I are not his puppets.
你就这么跟他说
Now you tell him that.
好  桥的事没戏了  没有挽回余地
Fine. The bridge deal is dead. There will be no saving it.
随你怎么折腾吧
Stick a knife through its heart and put an apple in its mouth.
我才不在乎呢
I won't shed a tear.
你们总统会把失败归咎于你
Your President will ascribe the failure to you.
我愿意冒这个险
I'll take the risk.
好好想想  副总统先生
Think strategically, Mr. Vice President.
你这是把我们往绝路上推
You're setting us on a very dangerous course.
你知道格兰特将军是如何击败李将军的吗
Do you know how Grant defeated Lee?
他的人更多  仅此而已
He had more men. That's all.
而且他愿意让他们去送死
And he was willing to let them die.
是屠杀  而非策略  赢得了战争
It was butchery, not strategy, which won the war.
塔斯克先生和我有丰厚资源可以利用
Mr. Tusk and I have great resources at our disposal.
把你们的钱加起来
Add up all your billions together,
相当于斯洛伐克的国内生产总值
and you get the GDP of Slovakia.
我背后是美利坚合众国的联邦政府
I have the federal government of the United States of America.
你们的钱吓不倒我
Your money doesn't intimidate me.
你最多能买到影响力
The most that you can buy is influence.
但我可以利用宪法施压
But I wield Constitutional authority.
最强大的军队并不总是能取胜
The strongest army doesn't always win.
毛主席从几千人的军队起步
Mao started out with only a few thousand men.
最终打下了半个亚洲
They took over half a continent.
毛主席已经死了  他的中国也死了
Mao is dead. And so is his China.
但我没死
But I'm not.
目前还没有
Not yet.
别忘了  你的祖先为战败的一方而战
Don't forget. Your ancestor fought for the losing side.
成者王  败者寇
There is no sacred ground for the conquered.
我们这里有九千余台服务器  分属几百家客户
We have over 9,000 servers here, utilized by several hundred clients.
从小企业到大公司都有
Everything from small businesses to major corporations.
最大的客户都有谁
What are some of the largest clients?
这里最大的是美国电话电报公司
The largest here is AT&T.
他们的服务器占了这层大半的空间
Their servers occupy more than half of the floor space.
能让我看看吗
And can you show me?
当然
I am.
这边走
Right this way.
你昨晚有没有去见冯
Did you or did you not meet with Feng last night?
这话从何说起  雷蒙德
Where is this coming from, Raymond?
回答我  弗兰克
Answer the question, Frank.
上次谈话后我就没联系过他了  总统先生
I have not contacted him since you and I spoke, Mr. President.
完全按照您的要求
Just as you instructed me to do.
冯可不是这么说的
Not according to Feng.
你不是也不许见他吗  雷蒙德
I believe you were also instructed to avoid him too, Raymond.
他自己找上门来的  我只是接了电话
He reached out to me. I just answered the call.
我们事先有明确的协议  弗兰克
We had clear, prearranged terms, frank.
私下接触了数月
Months of back-channeling.
我在第一线  总统先生
I am on the front lines, Mr. President.
我的亲身体会是
And I can tell you firsthand
我们现在面对的这个国家
that we are dealing with a regime
不仅有事隐瞒
that is not being forthright and
而且会利用任何风吹草动
will seize upon the faintest whiff of trepidation.
这是次考验
This is a test.
看我们被逼到什么境地会投降
To see how far they can push us before we break.
别让他们得逞  中止谈判
Do not play their game. End the talks.
我们不能反应过度
We can't overreact here.
他们中止了商贸联委会的谈判
Well, they walked away from the Joint Commission.
我们也可以中止峰会
We can walk away from the Summit.
经济损失难以估量  市场会
The economic fallout would be catastrophic. The market would--
要么向这个新兴超级大国卑躬屈膝也行
Or we can just kowtow and submit to the new reigning superpower.
别夸大其词  弗兰克
Don't be hyperbolic, Frank.
我们可是在跟全球四分之一的人口打交道
Well, we are dealing with one quarter of the world's population.
总统先生  这会酿成大错的
Mr. President, you would be making a disastrous mistake.
你到底效忠谁  雷蒙德
Where are your allegiances, Raymond?
是冯山德还是美国
With Xander Feng or to the United --?
你怎么敢质疑我的
Don't you dare question me about --
行了  安静
All right. Silence.
我犯了两个错误
There were two mistakes. Both of them mine.
第一个错误是允许你  雷蒙德
The first was allowing you, Raymond,
让你的商业伙伴参与谈判
to enlist your business partner for these talks.
我只是想
I was simply trying to --
而第二个错误就是让你去  弗兰克
And the second was enlisting you, Frank.
不但没把话说清楚
Instead of clarity,
还造成误解  外交表现糟糕
we got miscommunication. That's poor diplomacy.
总统先生  听我说
Mr. President, listen --
不  你们的话我都听过了
Oh, no. I've listened. To both of you.
但只听到了互相谴责
And all I've heard is accusations.
如果你们谁都不愿负责  那我来
Now if neither of you will take responsibility, I will.
我们撤出
We're pulling out.
并非是听从你的意见  弗兰克
That's not because you suggested it, Frank.
而是因为你协商失败
It's because you've made such a mess of these negotiations
让我不得不表现出强硬态度
that I have no other choice than a show of strength.
你们两个都让我很失望
You've both disappointed me greatly.
总统先生
Mr. President --
总统已离线
The President has left the call.
雷蒙德  你还在吗
Raymond, are you still there?
这是他二十年来第一次
That's the first time he's ever hung up on me
挂我电话
in 20 years.
为你难过
Oh. I feel for you.
再见  弗兰克
Goodbye, Frank.
现在  杀戮开始
And the butchery begins.
从这排起  到后面七排全是
It's all the way down this row and the next seven rows over.
你想进去看看  是吧
Now you wanted to see inside one, right?
是  那就太好了
Yeah, that would be great.
进去吧
Go ahead.
其实没什么好看的
There's not much to it, actually.
就是一堆硬盘和电线
Just a lot of hard drives and wires.
说到文件备份  如果突然停电
So in terms of back-up, if the power goes down,
比如碰上自然灾害
some natural disaster hits,
龙卷风或地震之类的  要怎么
like a storm, or an earthquake, what exactly --?
-趴在地上  -不许动
- On the ground. - Freeze!
-不  我  -立刻趴下
- No, no, I  - right now.
-趴下  立刻趴下  -我说了趴下
- On the ground! On the ground now! - I said on the fucking ground.
跟我同车回特区吧
Why don't you ride back to D.C. with me?
我们有事要谈
We need to discuss something.
怎么了
What's up?
我们车里谈
We'll talk about it in the car.
今天  我们在陆路战役游客中心破土动工
Today, we break earth on the Overland Campaign Visitors Center.
这样我们的后代
So that generations to come
能深刻体会这片圣地的重要意义
will fully absorb the importance of this hallowed ground,
铭记这片战役打响的荒野
the wilderness where the campaign commenced.
奥古斯都  请你来好吗
Augustus. Would you do the honor?
请为逝者默哀祈祷
And now a moment of silence and prayer for the dead.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
天佑美国
And God bless the United States of America.
刚收到消息
I just heard.
我们抓到卢卡斯·古德温了
We got Lucas Goodwin.
"人民币被刻意低估"是长期困扰中美经贸关系的一个焦点议题
多年来  美国国会一直指责中国政府刻意压低人民币币值
使中国产品价格低廉  出口后占据价格优势
许多议员将美国的对华的巨大贸易逆差  美国国内制造业的萧条
均归咎于人民币币值的被低估
在这个问题上立场最强硬的是国会中的民主党议员
他们背后大多有美国工会的支持
很多议员家乡有大量从事制造业的选民
过去这些年  美国国会通过听证会和立法等多种形式
向中国政府施压  该问题也是中美经济事务会谈争论的焦点
但白宫在汇率问题上的立场要软得多
小布什政府一直顶住国会的压力  拒绝将中国政府列为"汇率操纵国"
奥巴马虽然在竞选时接受了工会的巨额捐款
但上任后也没有在这个问题上满足国会的强硬要求
白宫非常清楚地认识到  如果在这一问题上同中国硬碰硬
导致贸易战  其结果将是两败俱伤
所以本届美国政府一直拒绝公开将中国列为"汇率操纵国"
2005年中国进行汇率改革之后  人民币一直稳中有升
中美之间的汇率问题也逐渐降温  一些美国智库的专家认为
即使美国现在决定到世贸组织就这一问题向中国提起诉讼
比起5年前来  胜诉的可能性也非常之小